<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Real-Time Commenting System in React on Alessio Franceschi</title><link>https://alessiofranceschi.dev/series/real-time-commenting-system-in-react/</link><description>Recent content in Real-Time Commenting System in React on Alessio Franceschi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright Alessio Franceschi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alessiofranceschi.dev/series/real-time-commenting-system-in-react/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Emoji Reactions for Comments - Building a Real-Time Commenting System in React [Part 3/3]</title><link>https://alessiofranceschi.dev/blog/react-commenting-system-part-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alessiofranceschi.dev/blog/react-commenting-system-part-3/</guid><description>In the first part of this series we built the basics of a commenting system while in the second one we finally added nested comments. In this third and final article we&amp;rsquo;ll add Emoji Reactions. This is going to be useful because people can interact with your content without the need to write a comment. An alternative would be a Reddit-like voting system, but I think that emojis will add a bit of color to our comments, so I decided to go for them.</description></item><item><title>Making Nested Comments - Building a Real-Time Commenting System in React [Part 2/3]</title><link>https://alessiofranceschi.dev/blog/react-commenting-system-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alessiofranceschi.dev/blog/react-commenting-system-part-2/</guid><description>In the previous part of this series we created the foundations of this project and now we have a basic commenting system where we can create and display comments in real time. This time we&amp;rsquo;re going to add some extra functionalities, like nested comments and markdown support.
Table Of Contents Nested Comments How to do Nested Comments Create a Child Comment Markdown Support reCAPTCHA Nested Comments There are a lot of ways to do nested comments and some of them may work better than my method, but for what we need and use (real time updates and Sanity.</description></item><item><title>Building a Real-Time Commenting System in React [Part 1/3]</title><link>https://alessiofranceschi.dev/blog/react-commenting-system/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alessiofranceschi.dev/blog/react-commenting-system/</guid><description>One of my latest projects is an entire blog built with Next.js, a framework based on React. One of the features I wanted was a commenting system, but none of those already available were interesting for me and I wanted full control on the features and the data. Because of that, I decided to create my own commenting system. This article is meant to show the process of creating it and there’s a repo on GitHub with the full code for reference.</description></item></channel></rss>